<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on English 2 Final: Charlemagne</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on English 2 Final: Charlemagne</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Background Information</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/background-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/background-information/</guid>
      <description>Charles I, known as Charlemagne was the King of the Lombards, and later the King of the Franks and was an emperor of Europe during the reign of the Franks.
He was born on April 2nd April, 747 CE to Pepin the Short and Bertrada of Loan. His early life was a tumtulous time since he was born before his parents were married, something that would declare him as illegimate during that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise to Power</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/rise-to-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/rise-to-power/</guid>
      <description>Charlemagne&amp;rsquo;s rise to power was one rife with corruption and nepotism. His father, Pippin III&amp;rsquo;s offical title was &amp;ldquo;Mayor to the Palace&amp;rdquo;, an assistant to the the King and royals during Merovingian dynasty. It is widely spectulated by historians that he actually held much more power than his title would suggest. Pippin III quickly rose to power, ascending to the throne of the Frankish Kingdom after the death of Childeric III, ending the Merovingian dynasty&amp;rsquo;s rule over Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legacy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/legacy/</guid>
      <description>Charlemagne&amp;rsquo;s legacy stretches close to two millennium, from 600CE to 2100CE and beyond. Among the most famous and consequential parts of his legacy is his military strategy. He promoted the use of mercenaries rather than a standing army. This provided many advantages to the Frankish Empire including:
 Lower costs to run Improved public opinion as people weren&amp;rsquo;t force to fight in wars A faster activation of military forces across the empire  Charelmagne&amp;rsquo;s legacy also leaves a lasting impression on the European continent, being the last ruler to unite Western Europe until the European Union in the early 1990s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Military Accomplishments</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/further-expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/further-expansion/</guid>
      <description>Charlemagne&amp;rsquo;s military accomplishments span over 40 years from the late 760s to the mid 810s CE. Among his most well known accomplishments include the Saxton, Byzantine, and Slavic wars. ALl were succesful expeditions that expanded Frankish control over Europe.
Victory over the Saxons in the Saxon War His largest and most well known accomplishment is his victory over the Saxons in the Saxon Wars from 772 to 804 CE. This war was among the most arduous wars in history due to the lives lost and damage done.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
